<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Teawd's blog#all</title>
<description>Full size posts from teawide.xyz/blog/all</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/all.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://teawide.xyz/blog/all.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
    <title>Complexity in art</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/complexity_in_art.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/complexity_in_art.html</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[


<div class="date">
    
    Posted: 20.07.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#complexity-in-art" id="complexity-in-art">
Complexity in art</a></h3>
<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/art.html">#art</a>
    <a href="/blog/personal.html">#personal</a>
</div>
<p>
I might be stating the obvious, but I don't think there is any objective value
to an art piece, except, maybe, it's historical value.
<br>
What I wanna talk about, is what makes an art pirece feel more valuable to me.
One obvious thing is the context. A lot of my favorite music and visual
artwork comes from games and movies I really like. I'd say it could be
thought of as personal historical value, it makes you remember the story and
its characters. Another thing is complexity.
</p>
<h5>
   Hiding in plain sight
</h5>
<p>
   One way to achieve complexity, is to have details or shapes that are not
   obvious on first viewing. A great example is this Hyper Light Drifter
   artwork I have as a poster. 
<a href="https://www.fangamer.com/products/hld-poster-fallen">
<img src="/resources/HLD/poster.png" id="smallimg"
alt="https://www.fangamer.com/products/hld-poster-fallen"/>
</a>
   Can you see a hand and a skull of a giant that form the rock?
   Some other details require familiarity with the game to notice. Discovering
   these was very satisfying.
</p>
<h5>
   Telling a story
</h5>
<p>
   A lot of art also tries to convey some idea or commentary. Sometimes it's
   explicit, sometimes hidden in metaphors and puzzles. I love when an artpiece
   leaves a lot to interpretation, a great example I can think of is <a
   href="https://www.youtube.com/c/vewnscape/videos">vewns animations</a>:
   surface level topics and ideas are clear, others require multiple watches
   and some thinking to understand, but still leave some ambiguity.
   Unfortunately, I'm not the best at deciphering metaphors, and even worse at
   trying to come up with a metaphor that could convey some of my feelings or
   ideas.
</p>
<h5>
   Putting secrets
</h5>
<p>
    Doesn't really add complexity in the same sense, but
   what I recently came to like to do is putting ARG-like hidden messages in
   some of the art I make. 
   It's mostly to satisfy those like me, who like those kinds
   of things.
</p>
<p>
   On that note here's an art piece I finished recently. 
   It's inspired by the art of False Noise, Hyper Light Drifter, and
   Etiene Crauss. In 3 variants, because I couldn't decide on a 
   color palette.
</p>
<div class="row">
    <div class="column">
        <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_8x.png">
        <img src="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_8x.png" alt="abstract pixel art"/>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="column">
        <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_h_8x.png">
        <img src="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_h_8x.png" alt="abstract pixel art"/>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="column">
        <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_i_8x.png">
        <img src="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_i_8x.png" alt="abstract pixel art"/>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>
<p>
    Thanks for reading my surface level thoughts on art. 
    And while these complexities are cool, I don't want to overthink them,
    so expect some more "simple" art.
</p>
<p>
   BTW my art and project files are licenced under CC0.
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa.kra">.kra file (634KB)</a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Speech to text diary scripts</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/speech_to_text_diary_scripts.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/speech_to_text_diary_scripts.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[


<div class="date">
    
    Posted: 10.04.2022
</div>

<h3><a href="#speech-to-text-diary-scripts" id="speech-to-text-diary-scripts">
        Speech to text diary scripts </a> </h3>
<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
        <a href="/blog/tech.html">#tech</a>
        <a href="/blog/linux.html">#linux</a>
</div>
<p>
First of all, this blog post is about a somewhat specific problem. Despite
this, I think it is quite useful to most readers looking for some Linux
knowledge as the tools I used are very general. Let's start with the
explanation of
</p>
<h4>
   The problem 
</h4>
<p>
   Sometimes I have good ideas when I'm outside. Sometimes I really wanna
   preserve these ideas, but it's very inconvenient to use phone keyboards,
   especially on the move. One solution is recording my voice. But then, I
   would want to transfer those recordings to my computer for future reference.
   But what if I also want to read the text version of those voice recordings?
   Let's handle these problems one at a time.
</p>
<h4>
   Syncthing files
</h4>
<h5>
   Syncthing 
</h5>
<p>
<a href="https://syncthing.net/">
   Syncthing</a> is an open source cross-platform program that can sync folders
   accross multiple devices. It's perfect for this problem, as it allows for
   P2P syncing (for example from a phone to a computer).
   <br>
   It's very easy to set up aswell, you download it on both devices, open a
   browser (Synthing has a web frontend) tab on 127.0.0.1:8384 and scan the ID
   QR with your phones camera. Then share whatever is the folder that has your
   audio recordings.
</p>
<p>
    If your init system is systemd, to start synthing (and enable autostart
    at boot) you can run (where USER is your linux user):
</p><p>
    systemctl enable syncthing@USER.service --now
</p><p>
   Synthing has configuration options for encryption and file filtering.
   If you want more robust syncing, you could also host a Syncthing instance 
   on a server.
</p>
<h4>
   Speech to text 
</h4>
<p>
   To convert my speech to text I use the SpeechRecognition python package:
   </p><p>
      pip install SpeechRecognition 
   </p><p>
   It supports many speech recognition options, including offline ones.
   It's also really easy to use, check 
   <a href="https://github.com/TeaWhyDee/public-scripts/blob/master/phone_diary/recognize.py">
      my script</a>.
</p>
<p>
    Options (present in my script as comments):
    <ul>
        <li>
            Pocketsphinx (low-accuracy offline option): 
            </p><p>
                pip install pocketsphinx
            </p><p>
        </li>
        <li>
            Google translate (has a limit on length)
        </li>
        <li>
            Google cloud (free, requires registration) 
        </li>
    </ul>
</p>
<p>
There are also other online and offline options.
<a href="https://pypi.org/project/SpeechRecognition/">
    (SpeechRecognition documentation)</a>
</p>
<h4>
    Storing recorings in notes
</h4>
<h5>
   Vimwiki 
</h5>
<p>
    I use vimwiki 
    <a href="https://github.com/vimwiki/vimwiki">
       vimwiki</a> (a (neo)vim plugin) that makes managing markdown files in a
   wiki-like manner extremely easy. Vimwiki also has a diary option. To store
   the recording path and text in my notes, I wrote a few scripts.
</p>
<p>
    The speech-to-diary.sh script calls the speech recognition script 
    on a selected file, appends transcription to a vimwiki diary and 
    (optionally) moves the voice recording to the vimwiki folder.
    it has a bunch of flags, you can get a help message by running:
    </p><p>
       ./speech-to-diary.sh -h 
    </p><p>
</p>
<p>
    The text that it puts looks like this:
    </p><p>
        20220328_162342.m4a 16:24:05  <br>
        Whatever speech recognition returned <br>
        /home/tea/vimwiki/diary/resources/20220328_162342.wav
    </p><p>
    I have a vim shortcut that plays an audio file under the cursor so that
    I can also listen to it if the transcription is not accurate enough.
</p>
<p>
   If you don't use vim or vimwiki, you can just change the last 
   line of the script to save the text to a file of your choosing.
</p>
<h4>
   Tying it all together 
</h4>
<h5>
   Actual Linux knowledge 
</h5>
<p>
   Now, we need a way to react to new files appearing in the syncing 
   directory. For that, we can use the linux inotify interface, that 
   waits for changes in files. For syncthing, the following command
   works:
   </p><p>
       inotifywait -c -r -m -e attrib $PATH_TO_WATCH
   </p><p>
   You can also see it used in a script. Be sure to read the readme
   on the repo for some additional information on setting up
   a systemd service (if you don't know how).
</p>
<p>
   Now, if you autostart syncthing and the watchscript at system boot, it 
   will process all new audio files.
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="https://github.com/TeaWhyDee/public-scripts/tree/master/phone_diary">
       GH Repo</a>
    <a href="https://pypi.org/project/SpeechRecognition/">
       SpeechRec docs</a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Simple video editing with MPV</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/simple_video_editing_with_mpv.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/simple_video_editing_with_mpv.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[


<div class="date">
    
    Posted: 13.03.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#simple-video-editing-with-mpv" id="simple-video-editing-with-mpv">
 Simple video editing with MPV </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
        <a href="/blog/tech.html">#tech</a>
        <a href="/blog/linux.html">#linux</a>
</div>
<p>
MPV is one of my favorite open source projects. It's a simple-looking 
video player with an enormous amount of features while also being 
highly extensible through the lua programming language.
</p>
<h4>
   MPV-splice Script 
</h4>
<p>
    MPV-splice is a script that allows you to use MPV as a video editor.
    You set the start and end timings for fragments, and then 
    the script cuts the video and concatenates the fragments.
</p>
<p>
   I made a fork of it to extend it's abilities.
   <ul>
       <li>
           I added an option to automatically upload
            the video (to any platform, but the default config works for Streamable).
       </li>
       <li>
           I added an option to reencode the video, making the timings frame perfect.
           By default, the script does not reencode the video, allowing for extremely 
           fast results.
       </li>
       <li>
           I fixed the editing of online videos. The script will only download the 
           selected portions of the video, which allows you to cut out fragments of even
           hours long YouTube videos for example.
       </li>
   </ul>
</p>
<p>
   Another useful script I forked is 8mb, which compresses your video to 8mb, changing
   it's FPS and resolution to appropriate values.
</p>
<div class="links">
   <a href="https://github.com/TeaWhyDee/mpv-yt-splice">mpv-splice repo</a>
   <a href="https://github.com/TeaWhyDee/public-scripts">public-scripts(includes 8mb)</a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Hyper Light Drifters magnificent sound</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/hyper_light_drifters_magnificent_sound.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/hyper_light_drifters_magnificent_sound.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[


<div class="date">
    
    Posted: 06.03.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#hyper-light-drifters-magnificent-sound" id="hyper-light-drifters-magnificent-sound">
 Hyper Light Drifters magnificent sound </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
        <a href="/blog/personal.html">#personal</a>
</div>
<p>
I first played Hyper Light Drifter 4 years ago, it quickly
became one of my favorite games. Recently, during some stressful times,
I decided to listen to it's soundtrack again. At the end, I cried.
    <a href="/resources/HLD/screenshot.png">
    <img src="/resources/HLD/screenshot.png" alt="screenshot"/>
    </a>
</p>
<h4>
   Hyper Light Drifter
</h4>
<p>
   The game is set in a post-apocalyptic 
   world, where nature has overtaken most structures
   and the survivors have either gone mad and murderous
   or gone into hiding trying preserve what's little left of the old world.
   It hits every point for me: 
   great exploration, hard but fair challenge and combat,
   simple but fun mechanics, awe-inspiring art and animation. And
   of course its dialogue-less story.
</p>
<h4>
   Echoes of the dead world 
</h4>
<p>
    What really made this game so special for me though in its music
    and sound design. 
    Composed by the great Disasterpeace, the music stands on it's own 
    unlike anything I've ever heard. The uniqueness and
    the impressionistic style of it perfectly intertwines with 
    the cryptic and beautiful world of Hyper Light Drifter.
    <video controls src="/resources/HLD/HLD2.mp4" alt="game footage"/>
</p>
<p>
    The music captures the feeling of every space you encounter -
    be it vast underground catacombs or a calm forest growing on 
    the remains of giant war machines, the echoes of which you 
    can hear in the distance - transitioning
    seemlessly from one area to another. The game also knows 
    when to use silence, leaving you with the ambience of the area.
</p>
<p>
   Replaying the game I noticed so many new details, nearly every area 
   has some effect on the soundtrack, you can hear the crackling of 
   thousand year old trees and the slight buzz of ancient technologies.
   <br> And this guy playing his guitar :)
   <video controls src="/resources/HLD/HLD3.mp4" alt="game footage"/>
</p>
<p>
    My favorite track is titled "Panacea", 
    the feelings it envokes in me is 
    unmatched by any other music-piece. It perfectly captured
    my melancholic mood. It let me cry out all of my frustrations 
    and I'm grateful for that.
</p>
<p>
   I don't like spoilers. And this post was as spoiler-free as I could get it.
   I didn't show any big encounters, any big reveals. But I hope you will look
   more into this game and listen to every little detail on your playthrough!
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="https://www.heartmachine.com/hyper-light-drifter"> HLD official website </a>
    <a href="https://music.disasterpeace.com/album/hyper-light-drifter"> Soundtrack (Bandcamp) </a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Music Playing: Local n Remote</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/music_playing_local_and_remote.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/music_playing_local_and_remote.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[


<div class="date">
    
    Posted: 20.02.2022
    | Updated: 23.02.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#music-players-local-&-remote" id="music-players-local-&-remote">
 Music Playing: Local & Remote </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
        <a href="/blog/linux.html">#linux</a>
        <a href="/blog/tech.html">#tech</a>
</div>
<p>
This blog-post is about my experience of playing music on Linux, although pretty much all
software I mention here works on Windows, Mac, Linux.. and even Android.
</p>
<h4>
   Browser as a Music Player 
</h4>
<p>
   The most basic way to play music is using some website.
   Most people prefer Spotify, but I personally hate it's interface 
   almost as much as I hate subscription services.
</p>
<p>
   For the longest time I've been using 
   <em class="orange">
       Soundcloud</em>, it has most music I like, 
   especially the quirky electronic type, all for free.
    It also allows you to upload songs without 
    any additional setup. But,
   of course, there are songs that are not on there. 
   The worst part is that some more main-stream artists
   have their songs region-locked or only available with
   soundcloud premium.
</p>
<h4>
   Local Music Library 
</h4>
<p>
   A year back I decided to begin storing my music locally.
   This approach ensures that I have access to all my
   favorite music, in best quality, offline, forever.
</p>
<p>
   It is honestly really freeing and opened a bunch of 
   possibilities for me.
</p>
<h5>
   DeaDBeeF Music Player 
</h5>
<p>
   I first settled on DeaDBeeF, as it's highly customisable,
   extensible and actively developed.
</p>
<p>
   Configuring takes some time to get used to. 
   You have to enable 'design mode' in the 'View' submenu to 
   start adding and removing panes. It allows you to use a lot of 
   GTK3 (UI library) widgets to structure your window 
   however you like. 
   <a href="/resources/music_playing/deadbeef_screenshot.png">
       <img src="/resources/music_playing/deadbeef_screenshot.png" alt=""/>
   </a>
   You can find my config in the GitHub repo linked below. 
</p>
<p>
    I especially like the visualization plugins that I found.
    On Arch-based systems it is extremely easy to install plugins:
    </p><p>
        yay -S deadbeef-plugin-spectrogram-gtk3-git \ <br>
        deadbeef-plugin-musical-spectrum-gtk3-git \ <br>
        deadbeef-plugin-rating \ <br>
        deadbeef-plugin-waveform-gtk3-git <br>
    </p><p>
    Some plugins are configured through settings, others through
    the right-click menu.
</p>
<p>
   There are 2 main problems with DeaDBeeF for me:
</p>
   <ul>
       <li>
           Lack of dynamic playlists or being able to go though
            artsts/albums without creating playlists for them manually.
        </li>
        <li>
            No playback queue display (it only shows the song position
            in the queue next to it).
        </li>
   </ul>
<p>
   Both of these features are in plans so at some point in the future
   I hope we'll get them.
</p>
<h5>
   MPD Music Server
</h5>
<p>
   Recently I started using 
   <a href="https://github.com/MusicPlayerDaemon/MPD">
      MPD</a>. It is even more technical than
   DeaDBeeF. It allows you to connect to it through a socket.
</p>
<p>
   All of it might sound scary but all you need to do to set it up 
   is create 1 config file. There are a lot of clients that 
   allow you to connect to an MPD server with relatively conventional
   interfaces. I am currently using 
   <a href="https://github.com/cdrummond/cantata">
      Cantata</a>, as it's the most feature rich one I could find.
</p>
<p>
   The great thing about MPD is that you can connect as many clients 
   as you want and they all will be synchronized with each other.
   There are clients for scrobbling your music to 
   <a href="https://last.fm">
      last.fm</a> (with <em>mpdas</em>),
  setting your discord 'rich presense' and controlling 
  playback with media keys or a notification (with <em>mpdris2</em>).
  It's the most modular music playing experience and I love it.
  My config looks like this:
 </p><p>
     music_directory    "~/Music" <br>
     db_file            "~/.config/mpd/database" <br>
     playlist_directory "~/.config/mpd/playlists" <br>
     sticker_file       "~/.config/mpd/sticker.sql" <br>
     log_file           "syslog" <br>
     auto_update "yes" <br>
     restore_paused "yes" <br>
<br>
     audio_output { <br>
     type    "pulse" <br>
     name    "pulse audio" <br>
     } <br>
<br>
audio_output { <br>
     type    "fifo" <br>
     name    "my_fifo" <br>
     path    "/tmp/mpd.fifo" <br>
     format  "22050:16:2" <br>
     } <br>
 </p><p> 
 'sticker_file' allows for custom music ratings (supported by Cantata),
 'fifo' audio output allows for latency-less audio
 visualization with 
 <a href="https://github.com/jarcode-foss/glava">
    Glava</a>.
    </p>
<p>
    To install everything I mentioned on Arch you would run: 
    </p><p>
        yay -S mpd mpd-discord-rpc-git mpdas mpdris2 cantata 
    </p><p>
</p>

<h4>
   Remote Music Library 
</h4>
<p>
   But what if I want to play my music on a device where 
   I don't have my audio library?
</p>
<h5>
   MPD Does it All 
</h5>
<p>
   You can create an http output by putting the following lines
   in your config:
   </p><p>
       audio_output { <br>
       type        "httpd" <br>
       name        "My HTTP Stream" <br>
       encoder        "lame" <br>
       port        "8000" <br>
       bitrate        "192" <br>
       format        "44100:16:1" <br>
       max_clients    "0" # 0=no limit <br>
       }  <br>
   </p><p>
   I host an MPD instance on my server and can control playback with 
   any client. On my phone I use
   <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.namelessdev.mpdroid/">
      MPDroid</a> (which can also stream the aduio).
    To stream audio on desktop you have to connect to the specified port
    through a music player that can play http streams, like mpv,
    or a web browser. 
    MPD clients, such as Cantata, can also play http audio streams.  
    The delay is a little annoying. There is a setup that allows for 0 delay
    playback ( with local mpd using a remote music library) I saw here:
    <a href="https://www.joram.io/blog/android-streaming-mpd/">
       www.joram.io/blog/android-streaming-mpd/</a>
</p>
<h4>
   But I want my recommendations!
</h4>
<h5>
   MPD :) 
</h5>
<p>
There is a 
<a href="https://github.com/saelz/mpd-auto-queue">
    client</a>
that automatically queues new songs based on
last.fm recommendations.
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="https://github.com/TeaWhyDee/public-dotfiles"> .files GitHub </a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Updating the Website</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/updating_the_website.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/updating_the_website.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[


<div class="date">
    
    Posted: 06.02.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#updating-the-website" id="updating-the-website">
 Updating the Website </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/tech.html">#tech</a>
</div>
<p>
Incomprehensible and unstructured jumble of code scattered 
across a range of highly specific tools that is one 
typo away from crumbling into ruins.
This is how I would describe
</p>
<h4>
   My static-site generator
</h4>
<p>
    To write a new article, I go to my blog-post directory,
    open a new file with vim and use a snippet (powered by 
    <a href="https://github.com/sirver/UltiSnips">
       UltiSnips</a>)
    that inputs an html template with todays date, it 
    also uses some python to automatically set ids 
    to article titles. <br>
    After that I am free to use any html I please inside 
    the article body. When I'm done, I set a flag 
    (an html comment) to indicate to my site generator
    that the article should be published/updated/deleted.
</p>
<p>
    Yep, it's all plaintext. I don't know what will happen
    if I mess up any of it.
    <br>
    This is how I roll.
</p>
<p>
    The site-generator itself is written in python and 
    just parses the file for the 
    fields I mentioned and then compiles all blog-posts 
    into html pages. It's NOT recommended for use yet but 
    you can 
    <a href="https://github.com/TeaWhyDee/teawd-site-generator">
       check it out</a>.
    What I would recommend is Luke Smith's 
    <a href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/lb">
       lb</a>.
</p>
<h4>
   So what's new? 
</h4>
<p>
    New and fresh additions to the site:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>
        Posts are now tagged and
        each tag has it's own page.
    </li>
    <li>
        Each blog-post now has an id, try clicking on
        the title of a post to get a link directly
        to it!
    </li>
</ul>
<p>
    I also rewrote a lot of the code to make future 
    changes easier. <br>
</p>
<h4>
   What's in plans?
</h4>
<p>
    I didn't have enough time to implement everything,
    in the future you can expect:
    <ul>
        <li>
            RSS feeds.
        </li>
        <li>
            An index page and a separate page for each post.
        </li>
        <li>
            Better explanation of the inner workings
            and a more general implementation.
        </li>
    </ul>
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="https://github.com/TeaWhyDee/teawd-site-generator">GitHub repo</a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Writing GUI to make weird designs</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/writing_gui_to_make_weird_designs.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/writing_gui_to_make_weird_designs.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[


<div class="date">
    
    Posted: 30.01.2022 | Updated: 06.02.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#writing-gui-to-make-weird-designs" id="writing-gui-to-make-weird-designs">
 Writing GUI to make weird designs </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/tech.html">#tech</a>
    <a href="/blog/art.html">#art</a>
</div>
<p>
    Hello! First week already proved challenging.
    Unfortunately I fell ill which also made it more difficult
    to finish something meaningful in time, but I have some results.
</p>
    <h4> The Idea </h4>
<p>
    I really like art based around very simple concepts.
    An example of such a concept is pixel art.
    The idea of pixel art is about as simple as it gets -
    you draw with little squares.
    So, I was doodling around trying to come up with something
    similar that looks cool.
    <a href="/resources/design_program/sketch.png">
    <img id="medimg" src="/resources/design_program/sketch.png" alt="sketch"/>
    </a>
    I came up with a modification of pixel art,
    with non-parallel lines and variable line width.
    I tried recreating it in
    inkscape, but quickly encountered multiple problems, like
    differently angled lines being at different distances from each
    other and the ends of lines looking off.
</p>
    <h4> How to GUI </h4>
<p>
    In the end I just decided to write my own program to make 
    this kind of designs. Only experience writing GUI I had 
    was using QT (C++); it was painful. I decided instead to 
    use Godot, as using a python-like language with dynamically
    typed variables seemed like a much better idea for a GUI.
</p>
<p>
    I had a few ideas I wanted to implement in my Goo-e: 
    shortcuts that the user can set/unset just by right-clicking 
    the element instead of going into settings menu and 
    searching for it there (I prototyped it but didn't yet use).
    Another idea was giving the user to ability to save
    any value as default (again, by right-clicking), for
    now I implemented it with a button next to a value.
</p>
    <h4> How do I optimize this ;-; </h4>
<p>
    <a href="/resources/design_program/ui_screenshot.png">
    <img src="/resources/design_program/ui_screenshot.png" alt="program screenshot"/>
    </a>
    As you can see the UI is incredibly bare-bones. Main features 
    are there: you can pan, zoom, draw and erase lines on a grid.
    Changing the angle of the grid is incredibly laggy as the code
    has to update a huge amount of individual nodes (objects).
    I will probably completely rewrite the entire program at 
    some point.
</p>
    <h4> Was it worth it? </h4>
<p>
    Writing an entire program just to make this very specific 
    type of designs might seems silly, especially considering
    how I realised that this effect can be achieved just by
    applying a simple image transform on a picture made using
    a normal square grid.
</p>
<p>
    Regardless, the experience is valuable.
    I felt good programming, abusing the hell
    out of Godot's signal system and other features that make 
    my life just a little bit easier. And damn does it feel 
    good accomplishing something at the end of the week and
    posting about it here. Here is something I doodled in 
    the program: see if you can figure out what it says, 
    each letter is made out of 1 line.
    <a href="/resources/design_program/design.png">
    <img src="/resources/design_program/design.png" alt="pic"/>
    </a>
    That's it for this week! Let's see what lies ahead :)
    
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="https://github.com/TeaWhyDee/angled-grid-draw">
        GitHub repo
    </a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Weekly Blog Posts</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/weekly_blog_posts.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/weekly_blog_posts.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[


<div class="date">
    
    Posted: 23.01.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#weekly-blog-posts" id="weekly-blog-posts">
 Weekly Blog Posts </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/personal.html">#personal</a>
</div>
<p>
    Hello. I've decided that I need to make weekly posts.
    And not just weekly posts, I need to have meaningful 
    weekly posts, about projects.
    I think this would motivate me to make plans and
    deliver on them. And to make sure that I don't 
    skip a week, I will donate 1000 rubles for every 
    week skipped to a charity of my choosing.
    <br>
        And well, since I just came up with this idea
    and didn't have a week to prepare, I will share
    some random abstract pixel art I made recently:
    
    <a href="/resources/work_day_pixel_art.png">
    <img id="medimg" src="/resources/work_day_pixel_art.png" alt="pixel art"/>
    </a>

</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="/resources/work_day_pixel_art_pixel.png">
        Original size pixel art
    </a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>15 Day Challenge: Drawing</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/15_day_challenge_drawing.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/15_day_challenge_drawing.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[

<div class="date">
    Posted: 31.07.2021
</div>
<h3><a href="#15-day-challenge-drawing" id="15-day-challenge-drawing">
 15 Day Challenge: Drawing </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/art.html">#art</a>
</div>
<p>
Me and my friend PizzArt decided to do 15 day long art challenges.
It is definitely a great way to make yourself learn something new.
You are motivated by 2 powerful things: deadlines - 1 piece everyday,
responsibility - your friend is expecting you, so you can't skip a
day for silly reasons.
<a href="/resources/ArtChal1/ArtChal_prev1.jpg">
    <img src="/resources/ArtChal1/ArtChal_prev1.jpg" alt="Compilation of 4 hand-drawn images"/>

</p>
<p>
4 of the images were drawn with pen and pencil, everything else
was drawn digitally in Krita (would recommend for painting).
I used filter and concept art brush packs from
<a href="https://docs.krita.org/en/resources_page.html">Krita's website</a>.
You can download the images and project files below if you want.
As you can see, the reference photos are also included.
<a href="/resources/ArtChal1/ArtChal_prev2.jpg">
    <img src="/resources/ArtChal1/ArtChal_prev2.jpg" alt="Compilation of digital drawings"/>

Check out PizzArt's drawings on
<a href="https://pizzart.github.io/blog.html"> his blog</a>.
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="/resources/ArtChal1/AC_Jul2021_pictures.zip">Drawings (24M)</a>
    <a href="https://mega.nz/file/QKA0iRDJ#TCjW6NNAAShraIpkb9hBOZwM3YFVc2a3B0EmGw_q2TI">.kra files (154M)</a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Website Artwork</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/website_artwork.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/website_artwork.html</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[

<div class="date"> 
    Posted: 26.07.2021 | Updated: 26.07.2021 
</div>
<h3><a href="#website-artwork" id="website-artwork">
 Website Artwork </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/art.html">#art</a>
</div>

<p>
This was the first time I ever used Inkscape. Surpisingly
easy to use, the interface also looks nice. 
Great open-source program! 
This post will (hopefully) be updated in the future.
<a href="/resources/Screenshot-Inkscape.png">
    <img src="/resources/Screenshot-Inkscape.png" alt="Screenshot of Inkscape"/>

</p>

<div class="links">
    <a href="/resources/website_content.zip"> .svg files (113K) </a>
    <a href="https://inkscape.org/"> Inkscape.org </a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item>

</channel>
</rss>

