<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Teawd's blog#art</title>
<description>Full size posts from teawide.xyz/blog/art</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/art.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://teawide.xyz/blog/art.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
    <title>Complexity in art</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/complexity_in_art.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/complexity_in_art.html</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[<!-- F - post, U - update, D - delete -->
<!-- U -->

<div class="date">
    <!-- Use :read !date_formatted_dots -->
    Posted: 20.07.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#complexity-in-art" id="complexity-in-art">
Complexity in art</a></h3>
<div class="tags">
    <!-- Use tag snippet -->
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/art.html">#art</a>
    <a href="/blog/personal.html">#personal</a>
</div>
<p>
I might be stating the obvious, but I don't think there is any objective value
to an art piece, except, maybe, it's historical value.
<br>
What I wanna talk about, is what makes an art pirece feel more valuable to me.
One obvious thing is the context. A lot of my favorite music and visual
artwork comes from games and movies I really like. I'd say it could be
thought of as personal historical value, it makes you remember the story and
its characters. Another thing is complexity.
</p>
<h5>
   Hiding in plain sight
</h5>
<p>
   One way to achieve complexity, is to have details or shapes that are not
   obvious on first viewing. A great example is this Hyper Light Drifter
   artwork I have as a poster. 
<a href="https://www.fangamer.com/products/hld-poster-fallen">
<img src="/resources/HLD/poster.png" id="smallimg"
alt="https://www.fangamer.com/products/hld-poster-fallen"/>
</a>
   Can you see a hand and a skull of a giant that form the rock?
   Some other details require familiarity with the game to notice. Discovering
   these was very satisfying.
</p>
<h5>
   Telling a story
</h5>
<p>
   A lot of art also tries to convey some idea or commentary. Sometimes it's
   explicit, sometimes hidden in metaphors and puzzles. I love when an artpiece
   leaves a lot to interpretation, a great example I can think of is <a
   href="https://www.youtube.com/c/vewnscape/videos">vewns animations</a>:
   surface level topics and ideas are clear, others require multiple watches
   and some thinking to understand, but still leave some ambiguity.
   Unfortunately, I'm not the best at deciphering metaphors, and even worse at
   trying to come up with a metaphor that could convey some of my feelings or
   ideas.
</p>
<h5>
   Putting secrets
</h5>
<p>
    Doesn't really add complexity in the same sense, but
   what I recently came to like to do is putting ARG-like hidden messages in
   some of the art I make. 
   It's mostly to satisfy those like me, who like those kinds
   of things.
</p>
<p>
   On that note here's an art piece I finished recently. 
   It's inspired by the art of False Noise, Hyper Light Drifter, and
   Etiene Crauss. In 3 variants, because I couldn't decide on a 
   color palette.
</p>
<div class="row">
    <div class="column">
        <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_8x.png">
        <img src="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_8x.png" alt="abstract pixel art"/>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="column">
        <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_h_8x.png">
        <img src="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_h_8x.png" alt="abstract pixel art"/>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="column">
        <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_i_8x.png">
        <img src="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_i_8x.png" alt="abstract pixel art"/>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>
<p>
    Thanks for reading my surface level thoughts on art. 
    And while these complexities are cool, I don't want to overthink them,
    so expect some more "simple" art.
</p>
<p>
   BTW my art and project files are licenced under CC0.
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa.kra">.kra file (634KB)</a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Writing GUI to make weird designs</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/writing_gui_to_make_weird_designs.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/writing_gui_to_make_weird_designs.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[<!-- U - post, U - update, D - delete -->
<!-- U -->

<div class="date">
    <!-- use :read !date_formatted_dots -->
    Posted: 30.01.2022 | Updated: 06.02.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#writing-gui-to-make-weird-designs" id="writing-gui-to-make-weird-designs">
 Writing GUI to make weird designs </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    <!-- Use tag snippet -->
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/tech.html">#tech</a>
    <a href="/blog/art.html">#art</a>
</div>
<p>
    Hello! First week already proved challenging.
    Unfortunately I fell ill which also made it more difficult
    to finish something meaningful in time, but I have some results.
</p>
    <h4> The Idea </h4>
<p>
    I really like art based around very simple concepts.
    An example of such a concept is pixel art.
    The idea of pixel art is about as simple as it gets -
    you draw with little squares.
    So, I was doodling around trying to come up with something
    similar that looks cool.
    <a href="/resources/design_program/sketch.png">
    <img id="medimg" src="/resources/design_program/sketch.png" alt="sketch"/>
    </a>
    I came up with a modification of pixel art,
    with non-parallel lines and variable line width.
    I tried recreating it in
    inkscape, but quickly encountered multiple problems, like
    differently angled lines being at different distances from each
    other and the ends of lines looking off.
</p>
    <h4> How to GUI </h4>
<p>
    In the end I just decided to write my own program to make 
    this kind of designs. Only experience writing GUI I had 
    was using QT (C++); it was painful. I decided instead to 
    use Godot, as using a python-like language with dynamically
    typed variables seemed like a much better idea for a GUI.
</p>
<p>
    I had a few ideas I wanted to implement in my Goo-e: 
    shortcuts that the user can set/unset just by right-clicking 
    the element instead of going into settings menu and 
    searching for it there (I prototyped it but didn't yet use).
    Another idea was giving the user to ability to save
    any value as default (again, by right-clicking), for
    now I implemented it with a button next to a value.
</p>
    <h4> How do I optimize this ;-; </h4>
<p>
    <a href="/resources/design_program/ui_screenshot.png">
    <img src="/resources/design_program/ui_screenshot.png" alt="program screenshot"/>
    </a>
    As you can see the UI is incredibly bare-bones. Main features 
    are there: you can pan, zoom, draw and erase lines on a grid.
    Changing the angle of the grid is incredibly laggy as the code
    has to update a huge amount of individual nodes (objects).
    I will probably completely rewrite the entire program at 
    some point.
</p>
    <h4> Was it worth it? </h4>
<p>
    Writing an entire program just to make this very specific 
    type of designs might seems silly, especially considering
    how I realised that this effect can be achieved just by
    applying a simple image transform on a picture made using
    a normal square grid.
</p>
<p>
    Regardless, the experience is valuable.
    I felt good programming, abusing the hell
    out of Godot's signal system and other features that make 
    my life just a little bit easier. And damn does it feel 
    good accomplishing something at the end of the week and
    posting about it here. Here is something I doodled in 
    the program: see if you can figure out what it says, 
    each letter is made out of 1 line.
    <a href="/resources/design_program/design.png">
    <img src="/resources/design_program/design.png" alt="pic"/>
    </a>
    That's it for this week! Let's see what lies ahead :)
    
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="https://github.com/TeaWhyDee/angled-grid-draw">
        GitHub repo
    </a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>15 Day Challenge: Drawing</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/15_day_challenge_drawing.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/15_day_challenge_drawing.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[<!-- U -->

<div class="date">
    Posted: 31.07.2021
</div>
<h3><a href="#15-day-challenge-drawing" id="15-day-challenge-drawing">
 15 Day Challenge: Drawing </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    <!-- Use tag snippet -->
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/art.html">#art</a>
</div>
<p>
Me and my friend PizzArt decided to do 15 day long art challenges.
It is definitely a great way to make yourself learn something new.
You are motivated by 2 powerful things: deadlines - 1 piece everyday,
responsibility - your friend is expecting you, so you can't skip a
day for silly reasons.
<a href="/resources/ArtChal1/ArtChal_prev1.jpg">
    <img src="/resources/ArtChal1/ArtChal_prev1.jpg" alt="Compilation of 4 hand-drawn images"/>

</p>
<p>
4 of the images were drawn with pen and pencil, everything else
was drawn digitally in Krita (would recommend for painting).
I used filter and concept art brush packs from
<a href="https://docs.krita.org/en/resources_page.html">Krita's website</a>.
You can download the images and project files below if you want.
As you can see, the reference photos are also included.
<a href="/resources/ArtChal1/ArtChal_prev2.jpg">
    <img src="/resources/ArtChal1/ArtChal_prev2.jpg" alt="Compilation of digital drawings"/>

Check out PizzArt's drawings on
<a href="https://pizzart.github.io/blog.html"> his blog</a>.
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="/resources/ArtChal1/AC_Jul2021_pictures.zip">Drawings (24M)</a>
    <a href="https://mega.nz/file/QKA0iRDJ#TCjW6NNAAShraIpkb9hBOZwM3YFVc2a3B0EmGw_q2TI">.kra files (154M)</a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Website Artwork</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/website_artwork.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/website_artwork.html</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[<!-- U -->

<div class="date"> 
    Posted: 26.07.2021 | Updated: 26.07.2021 
</div>
<h3><a href="#website-artwork" id="website-artwork">
 Website Artwork </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    <!-- Use tag snippet -->
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/art.html">#art</a>
</div>

<p>
This was the first time I ever used Inkscape. Surpisingly
easy to use, the interface also looks nice. 
Great open-source program! 
This post will (hopefully) be updated in the future.
<a href="/resources/Screenshot-Inkscape.png">
    <img src="/resources/Screenshot-Inkscape.png" alt="Screenshot of Inkscape"/>

</p>

<div class="links">
    <a href="/resources/website_content.zip"> .svg files (113K) </a>
    <a href="https://inkscape.org/"> Inkscape.org </a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item>

</channel>
</rss>

