<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Teawd's blog#personal</title>
<description>Full size posts from teawide.xyz/blog/personal</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/personal.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://teawide.xyz/blog/personal.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
    <title>Complexity in art</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/complexity_in_art.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/complexity_in_art.html</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[<!-- F - post, U - update, D - delete -->
<!-- U -->

<div class="date">
    <!-- Use :read !date_formatted_dots -->
    Posted: 20.07.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#complexity-in-art" id="complexity-in-art">
Complexity in art</a></h3>
<div class="tags">
    <!-- Use tag snippet -->
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/art.html">#art</a>
    <a href="/blog/personal.html">#personal</a>
</div>
<p>
I might be stating the obvious, but I don't think there is any objective value
to an art piece, except, maybe, it's historical value.
<br>
What I wanna talk about, is what makes an art pirece feel more valuable to me.
One obvious thing is the context. A lot of my favorite music and visual
artwork comes from games and movies I really like. I'd say it could be
thought of as personal historical value, it makes you remember the story and
its characters. Another thing is complexity.
</p>
<h5>
   Hiding in plain sight
</h5>
<p>
   One way to achieve complexity, is to have details or shapes that are not
   obvious on first viewing. A great example is this Hyper Light Drifter
   artwork I have as a poster. 
<a href="https://www.fangamer.com/products/hld-poster-fallen">
<img src="/resources/HLD/poster.png" id="smallimg"
alt="https://www.fangamer.com/products/hld-poster-fallen"/>
</a>
   Can you see a hand and a skull of a giant that form the rock?
   Some other details require familiarity with the game to notice. Discovering
   these was very satisfying.
</p>
<h5>
   Telling a story
</h5>
<p>
   A lot of art also tries to convey some idea or commentary. Sometimes it's
   explicit, sometimes hidden in metaphors and puzzles. I love when an artpiece
   leaves a lot to interpretation, a great example I can think of is <a
   href="https://www.youtube.com/c/vewnscape/videos">vewns animations</a>:
   surface level topics and ideas are clear, others require multiple watches
   and some thinking to understand, but still leave some ambiguity.
   Unfortunately, I'm not the best at deciphering metaphors, and even worse at
   trying to come up with a metaphor that could convey some of my feelings or
   ideas.
</p>
<h5>
   Putting secrets
</h5>
<p>
    Doesn't really add complexity in the same sense, but
   what I recently came to like to do is putting ARG-like hidden messages in
   some of the art I make. 
   It's mostly to satisfy those like me, who like those kinds
   of things.
</p>
<p>
   On that note here's an art piece I finished recently. 
   It's inspired by the art of False Noise, Hyper Light Drifter, and
   Etiene Crauss. In 3 variants, because I couldn't decide on a 
   color palette.
</p>
<div class="row">
    <div class="column">
        <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_8x.png">
        <img src="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_8x.png" alt="abstract pixel art"/>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="column">
        <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_h_8x.png">
        <img src="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_h_8x.png" alt="abstract pixel art"/>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="column">
        <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_i_8x.png">
        <img src="/resources/art/pawa/pawa_i_8x.png" alt="abstract pixel art"/>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>
<p>
    Thanks for reading my surface level thoughts on art. 
    And while these complexities are cool, I don't want to overthink them,
    so expect some more "simple" art.
</p>
<p>
   BTW my art and project files are licenced under CC0.
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="/resources/art/pawa/pawa.kra">.kra file (634KB)</a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Hyper Light Drifters magnificent sound</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/hyper_light_drifters_magnificent_sound.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/hyper_light_drifters_magnificent_sound.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[<!-- U - post, U - update, D - delete -->
<!-- U -->

<div class="date">
    <!-- Use :read !date_formatted_dots -->
    Posted: 06.03.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#hyper-light-drifters-magnificent-sound" id="hyper-light-drifters-magnificent-sound">
 Hyper Light Drifters magnificent sound </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    <!-- Use tag snippet -->
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
        <a href="/blog/personal.html">#personal</a>
</div>
<p>
I first played Hyper Light Drifter 4 years ago, it quickly
became one of my favorite games. Recently, during some stressful times,
I decided to listen to it's soundtrack again. At the end, I cried.
    <a href="/resources/HLD/screenshot.png">
    <img src="/resources/HLD/screenshot.png" alt="screenshot"/>
    </a>
</p>
<h4>
   Hyper Light Drifter
</h4>
<p>
   The game is set in a post-apocalyptic 
   world, where nature has overtaken most structures
   and the survivors have either gone mad and murderous
   or gone into hiding trying preserve what's little left of the old world.
   It hits every point for me: 
   great exploration, hard but fair challenge and combat,
   simple but fun mechanics, awe-inspiring art and animation. And
   of course its dialogue-less story.
</p>
<h4>
   Echoes of the dead world 
</h4>
<p>
    What really made this game so special for me though in its music
    and sound design. 
    Composed by the great Disasterpeace, the music stands on it's own 
    unlike anything I've ever heard. The uniqueness and
    the impressionistic style of it perfectly intertwines with 
    the cryptic and beautiful world of Hyper Light Drifter.
    <video controls src="/resources/HLD/HLD2.mp4" alt="game footage"/>
</p>
<p>
    The music captures the feeling of every space you encounter -
    be it vast underground catacombs or a calm forest growing on 
    the remains of giant war machines, the echoes of which you 
    can hear in the distance - transitioning
    seemlessly from one area to another. The game also knows 
    when to use silence, leaving you with the ambience of the area.
</p>
<p>
   Replaying the game I noticed so many new details, nearly every area 
   has some effect on the soundtrack, you can hear the crackling of 
   thousand year old trees and the slight buzz of ancient technologies.
   <br> And this guy playing his guitar :)
   <video controls src="/resources/HLD/HLD3.mp4" alt="game footage"/>
</p>
<p>
    My favorite track is titled "Panacea", 
    the feelings it envokes in me is 
    unmatched by any other music-piece. It perfectly captured
    my melancholic mood. It let me cry out all of my frustrations 
    and I'm grateful for that.
</p>
<p>
   I don't like spoilers. And this post was as spoiler-free as I could get it.
   I didn't show any big encounters, any big reveals. But I hope you will look
   more into this game and listen to every little detail on your playthrough!
</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="https://www.heartmachine.com/hyper-light-drifter"> HLD official website </a>
    <a href="https://music.disasterpeace.com/album/hyper-light-drifter"> Soundtrack (Bandcamp) </a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item><item>
    <title>Weekly Blog Posts</title>
    <guid>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/weekly_blog_posts.html</guid>
    <link>https://teawide.xyz/blog/post/weekly_blog_posts.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000
</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[<!-- U - post, U - update, D - delete -->
<!-- U -->

<div class="date">
    <!-- use :read !date_formatted_dots -->
    Posted: 23.01.2022
</div>
<h3><a href="#weekly-blog-posts" id="weekly-blog-posts">
 Weekly Blog Posts </a></h3>

<div class="tags">
    <!-- Use tag snippet -->
    <a href="/blog/all.html">#all</a>
    <a href="/blog/personal.html">#personal</a>
</div>
<p>
    Hello. I've decided that I need to make weekly posts.
    And not just weekly posts, I need to have meaningful 
    weekly posts, about projects.
    I think this would motivate me to make plans and
    deliver on them. And to make sure that I don't 
    skip a week, I will donate 1000 rubles for every 
    week skipped to a charity of my choosing.
    <br>
        And well, since I just came up with this idea
    and didn't have a week to prepare, I will share
    some random abstract pixel art I made recently:
    
    <a href="/resources/work_day_pixel_art.png">
    <img id="medimg" src="/resources/work_day_pixel_art.png" alt="pixel art"/>
    </a>

</p>
<div class="links">
    <a href="/resources/work_day_pixel_art_pixel.png">
        Original size pixel art
    </a>
</div>

    ]]></description>
    </item>

</channel>
</rss>

